WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -
A mountain's like a person.
Sing to it properly, it will
reflect your song back to you,
showing you where to
mine, where to tunnel...
And where to leave
the mountain untouched.
Father...
It's more than we ever imagined.
- King Durin, there is a...
- Enough!
Seize the Elf.
Elrond is as much a brother to me
as if he'd been fired
in my own mother's womb.
How dare you!
Invoke your mother's memory
to defend your decision
to betray your own kind?
It's you that's betrayed our kind!
You profane the crown you wear!
Leave it.
It's not yours anymore.
From shadow you came.
To shadow I bid you return!
You had that dream again
last night, didn't you?
In the dream, there's
a kind of... branch.
Under the stars.
It appears we're being followed.
I was sifting through Sadoc's old book.
I think it's some kinda directions.
Welcome to the lands of Rhûn.
Why you looking at it like that?
Like you've been here before.
Only in dreams.
Tell me your name.
I have had many names.
Where is Halbrand?
He is gone. And I doubt he will return.
And should he ever, none of
us are to treat with him again.
Elrond just informed me your
companion was not who he claimed.
He is not what I thought.
He is Sauron.
It is to be given directly
to Lord Celebrimbor.
He must be informed
that Halbrand is Sauron.
Forgive me, my lord, but a
messenger has just arrived.
Do we grant him entry?
- Mole-tail stew, mole-tail stew...
- Oh.
Wait.
- Too dear.
- What?
We're not paupers.
You're the one said we'd be wise
to tighten our purse strings.
Or were you not including
yourself when you said that?
Hmm?
You married a prince.
But now you're bound to an outcast.
I'm bound to the Dwarf I love.
And I wouldn't trade his heart
for a mine full of fire opals.
Be nice to have the opals, though.
Aye. It would.
Have you tried to talk to your father...
Disa, you know he will
never agree to see me.
That's not what I asked.
Why should I be the one
to ask for an audience?
He disowned me!
He's as stubborn as a stone leg.
You're gonna have better
luck tryna bend a brick.
You may as well f...
Disa?
Brace yourself.
I said brace yourselves!
Disa!
Durin.
No.
No, no, no, no.
These lands shall bear you
sweet blossoms once more.
My dear brother.
Lord Celebrimbor.
They did not tell me you had arrived.
What news?
I've had an unexpected visitor.
He has returned already?
Galadriel? Galadriel? Galadriel?
Are they not the seeds you planted?
Three rings
for the Elven-kings under the sky.
Seven for the Dwarf-lords
in their halls of stone.
Nine for mortal men doomed to die.
We should attack Mordor from the north.
We enter here, between the
Ered Lithui and the Ephel Arnen.
It would be wiser to
attack Adar from the east.
What of the whereabouts of Sauron?
Our spies indicate that Sauron was
last seen traveling into Mordor.
We believe he intends to supplant
Adar and claim his armies.
If we move swiftly,
we may be able to crush
two spiders with one boot.
And what says the Commander
of the Northern Armies?
Galadriel?
Um, we should send ships up the Anduin,
invade Mordor from the west.
See to the preparations.
It does not take the eye of an eagle
to see your thoughts
have flown far afield.
What troubles them?
Sauron may well have traveled to Mordor,
but we cannot be certain
that is where he remains.
What makes you say that?
Sauron...
sees himself not as
master of a barren waste,
but of all Middle-earth.
He seeks to rule it not
only through conquest,
but by bending the minds and wills
of all its peoples to his own.
And for that, he needs not armies...
but Rings.
And he cannot craft
them without Celebrimbor.
Sauron is alone, without army or ally.
Eregion is protected by two rivers
with miles of curtain wall of
dwarven stone, ten-foot thick.
Rest assured, Celebrimbor
and the secrets of his craft
are safe.
I tell you, some veiled evil
closes in on Celebrimbor.
Sauron's plan is in motion even now.
I know it.
How?
Since the wearing of
this Ring, I have felt...
perceived...
glimpses of the unseen world...
as dreams unbidden, coming
forth to crowd my waking mind.
You believe the Rings
have kindled your ability
to see that which has
not yet come to pass?
Have they kindled yours?
I have seen mountains crumbling.
Waters running dry. And clouds.
Black. Gathering over white towers.
- Then send me to Eregion.
- Galadriel...
- If Sauron is there, I will send word...
- You cannot face Sauron again.
It is said that once the
Deceiver obtains a being's trust,
he gains the ability to
sculpt their very thoughts.
To deceive not only their heart
and mind, but their eyes and ears.
To alter their very reality.
You have already been affected once.
Yes.
He knows my mind.
And I know his.
Which is why I must face him.
Why I alone can slay him.
You once considered him a friend.
- Halbrand was not a...
- Sauron.
You cannot face him alone.
Supposing... I was not alone?
Lord Celebrimbor regrets to inform
you he's unable to grant you entry.
Mightn't I speak with him directly?
My lord is occupied.
But he wishes you good
fortune on your journey.
Are you asking me to leave?
The Lord of Eregion is asking you.
Perhaps I'll just wait here.
Just in case he changes his mind.
- Is he gone?
- No. He refuses to leave, my lord.
Well, he can refuse all he cares to.
I promised Lady
Galadriel before she left
that I would never treat with him again.
Was there something more?
I believe he's injured, my lord.
Let him be.
He'll leave soon enough.
Messengers from Lindon should
arrive with news any day.
What tidings from the white wings?
Sauron's shadow is deepening.
It is said he has taken a new
form to deceive his enemies.
And the Istar?
I hear whispers from salt
scavengers and mûmakil thieves.
Whispers of an old man in rags,
traveling east with two halflings.
He is lost. Vulnerable.
But he will not be for long.
We must reach him before he
learns to harness his powers.
Perhaps, the blood I wasted
to bring you before me
should have been spent
on more useful servants.
Master.
One of the trackers you
sent out has returned.
Have you found him?
I didn't just find him.
I know how to capture him.
Heal the curse upon our flesh,
and I will bring you
the Istar in chains.
What makes you think
a mortal like yourself
could defeat an Istar
when my most powerful
acolytes could not?
The Istar will surrender to
me, because if he doesn't,
I will slaughter the
halflings he calls friends.
What about Doderick?
Doderick?
All right, all right. Andwise?
It is a fine name. Nevertheless,
it is not going to be mine.
I know.
Fredagard.
But don't you see?
No one can give you a name.
It is yours already.
It is who you are.
And when you hear it spoken,
you feel your heart glow.
You'll hear it one day.
I'm sure of it.
We'll find out who you are.
I knew it!
Says here if we turn northeast,
we can cut this leg
of the journey in half.
Over there. Come on!
My preference would be to avoid the path
on which we would run
out of water the first day
and die of heat the second.
But perhaps that is just me?
How about Doderick?
You already said Doderick.
No, I didn't.
- Yes, you did.
Ah, how fares the forager this time?
All I found was a scorpion
and a clump of cactus.
The scorpion stung me,
I fell over, and, well...
- That's how I found the cactus.
- That's how you found the cactus.
Couldn't you just, I don't know,
magic some more water into being?
He's afraid he'd lose
control again without a gand.
So we find a gand. S'plenty
of sticks all over the place.
Don't think it works that way, Pop.
Silence.
What is it?
On the wind. Can you hear that?
- Almost sounds like...
- Hooves.
They're still close. Mount up!
Who were they?
I don't know.
They're watching our trail.
Meaning, we'd be wise to find another.
We already have.
Nobody goes off-trail.
- Nobody walks alone.
Every garden has withered
since the earthquake.
It's not just the gardens.
Rumors abound of dark omens
across all the Dwarven realms.
Some say the mountain was cursed
when the prince let in that Elf.
You two wouldn't be trafficking
in conjecture, would you?
- No.
- Wouldn't dream of it.
Good. 'Cause a rumor's like a songbird.
May sound filling from afar, but
up close, it's an empty feast.
Then it isn't true?
That something terrible is happening?
We're about to prove it isn't.
- King Durin.
Disa.
Narvi, your report?
Sire.
Not long ago, a fire-mountain awoke.
And although it resides
far to our south,
the ground-shakes it produced
spread through the bones of
the earth all the way here,
collapsing our sun-shafts,
and with them, our
ability to grow crops.
Now, the obvious remedy
is to set the dig-teams to
work repairing the shafts
and sinking new ones. However...
Every Stone-singer you've brought here
has failed to identify
a safe path to dig.
I'm afraid that's true.
With your approval, sire,
we will find the light.
You have it.
For nine centuries,
the Stone-singers have fostered
our sacred connection to this rock.
And in all those years, not once,
not once have they ever
ceased to provide for us.
But now, whatever the cause,
the bond is broken.
The hand of darkness has
closed around Khazad-dûm.
Dig carefully, Delve-master.
Disa.
A moment?
Are you really going to make me ask?
Do you mean your
grandchildren? They're well.
They miss tugging your
beard, of course, but...
You needn't make this
harder than it already is.
Funny. I keep saying
the same thing to him.
Surely Durin knows I spoke in anger!
If that's an apology I hear,
King, try saying it to my husband.
Why should it be me who apologizes?
It was he who caused offense!
I tell you, he's...
Stubborn as a root-bound parsnip?
One more quality the two
of you have in common.
What you call "stubbornness,"
some Dwarves call "strength."
Oh, I imagine it does take
strength to carry a grudge so heavy.
To keep your wounded heart so
tightly bound, it can barely beat.
Aye, it does.
It truly does.
No wonder we can't hear the mountain.
Its King is deaf to the
sorrow of his own son.
Still your axe, Disa!
You want to show true strength?
Summon your son to you.
He'll answer.
But leave it to him and the
peaks of Zirakzigil will thaw
before this feud of yours will.
No sunlight yet.
Another dead end.
We're gonna have to work all night.
Oh, here we go.
Growing blisters, I see. No
shame in it. Even I've had 'em.
- Oh, y'have?
- Aye. When I was five!
Aye, palace hands.
Been polishing jewels all his life.
Don't fret, Prince, only 13 hours to go.
Aye. It's his fault we're in this mess.
And his father.
Eh?
Lay a finger on me again, I'll
bite it off at the knuckle.
How was the mine?
'Bout the same.
Where are the weans?
Said they weren't hungry. Again.
Well, I can't blame 'em.
This rye tastes like last year's bread.
It is last year's bread.
Why not trade for fresh
grain from the surface?
Splendid idea!
But who in the Dimrill Dale will we
find to convince your father of it?
- Don't start.
- Um... Let me think...
I said don't.
Ah, climb off your
high peak and apologize!
- You're giving me indigestion.
- Good! Now listen to your guts!
I am!
And they still say I was right.
If he hadn't have
thrown Elrond out to rot,
we'd have food enough for 500 years!
You think this is about food?
We can't hear the mountains anymore.
I'm afraid, Durin.
I'm afraid.
Disa... Come here.
We're Dwarves.
We'll find a way.
We always have.
How?
Our letters to Celebrimbor
have all gone unanswered.
I fear Sauron may be in Eregion.
The High King has consented to
send me and a small party there,
to ensure Celebrimbor
and his city are safe.
I'm asking you to join us.
As you are so fond of
reminding me, Galadriel,
I am but a politician.
And as such, you have
the High King's trust.
He believes in your steadfastness.
A dog is steadfast. And
quicker to follow on a leash.
He refuses to send me without you.
And why is that?
- You know the reason.
- I'm asking if you know it.
The High King believes, that if
I were to face the Enemy alone,
I may be vulnerable to deception.
And why would he think that?
Stop it, Elrond.
You've defied the High
King's orders before.
Why not do so now?
Because he is right.
Sauron used me.
And under his hand, I
was played like a harp
to a melody not of my choosing.
It was entirely of your choosing.
Sauron looked inside you,
plucked the very song of
your soul, note by note,
making himself out to be
exactly what you needed.
"The Lost King" who
could ride you to victory.
You gave him everything he wanted
and then thanked him for it.
And now he has done
the same to Gil-galad.
And to every Elf in Lindon.
And that is why we need you.
Help us navigate this labyrinth.
There is no navigating it.
The labyrinth is his.
As long as you stay in
it, you've already lost.
- He may well want you in Eregion...
- Please, Elrond.
I cannot let him in again.
I cannot.
He never left, Galadriel.
In choosing to wear those Rings,
you have all chosen to
become his collaborators.
I will have no part in it.
You promised me once,
"If but a whisper of a rumor"
of what I feared proved true,
you would not rest
until it was put right.
If our friendship ever
meant anything to you,
please leave.
Do you not wish to live in beauty?
Master Círdan, I
cannot trust these Rings.
What is beauty, when it
is born, in part, of evil?
No less beautiful.
Not to me.
Would you cast Rúmil's
verses into the flame,
because the poet was a drunkard?
Rúmil was a drunkard?
Do not ask of Daeron.
Insufferable.
But a voice,
a voice that could make the
very sun weep tears of fire.
Judge the work,
and leave judgment concerning
those who wrought it
to the judge who sees all things.
That feels impossible.
It is called humility.
And it is difficult for most.
But it is the truest form of sight.
I wish I could know your peace.
You can.
We do not yet fully
understand these Rings.
But look at the power they
exert over every form of life.
In Sauron's hands, they could
work an evil beyond reckoning,
dominating the minds and wills of all.
This is why they must
remain in the hands of Elves.
You are wise to fear this power, Elrond.
But do not let that fear blind you
to the ways it can be used for good.
For it is not your enemy,
that bears these Rings...
But your most trusted friends.
If you believe they have
strayed, do not abandon them,
but rather open your
eyes and guide them...
Before the darkness
spreads across Middle-earth,
and blinds us all.
You need to rest.
Certainly not, I...
Wake up!
What are you doin'? Get back here!
I saw it. I know I saw it. C'mon.
Poppy, he's not breathin' anymore!
There! Yes! Nori, I can see it!
See what?
Water.
How could someone who
hasn't eaten in so long
still weigh so much?
Quick sticks!
Please, oh, please, oh, please.
Hurry, Poppy!
Come on!
I got it.
Come on.
You're going to be all right.
Great goats, you're alive.
For a moment there, I thought
we'd lost... we'd lost you.
We're none of us, going
to lose each other.
I'd be crying 'cept my eyes are too dry.
Oh...
What is it?
You don't think...
It is not dissimilar from
the staff I saw in my dream.
Um, Nori...
Oh, we were just
having a drink of water.
Pängul niganvil!
What are you doin'?
Nori, get down!
Stop! Stop! Make it stop!
Why isn't he stopping it?
He can't!
Help us!
Nori!
I'm coming!
Hold on! Hold on!
Nori!
It's gone.
Has it?
I have called it ithildin.
Made from our last sliver of mithril.
Out of the moonlight,
it is all but invisible.
It is.
Quite invisible.
Our visitor, is he still...
The night is cold, my lord.
Shall I bring him a shawl?
Whatever the reason
for your presence here,
if you do not leave willingly,
you shall be removed by force.
I can treat with you no longer.
She said you'd say that.
Galadriel? You have spoken with her?
Well, haven't you?
I have not.
Not since she left for Lindon.
Then you know nothing
of what's happened?
Nothing of the Rings?
What of the Rings?
Have they worked?
You'd do better to ask her.
She's not here.
- You are.
- What about the High King?
Surely he wouldn't
neglect to send word of...
Oh, I see.
It's the oldest tale there is, isn't it?
The true creators toil
till their knuckles bleed
and then they come along, take
whatever profits them most,
and forget all about us.
I applaud your patience.
Where are you going?
There's no cause to stay
where I'm not wanted.
Wait.
Halbrand. Please. Tell me.
The Rings. Did they work?
They worked wonders.
Then, the Elves...
Yes.
And, uh, Lindon?
- Are you weeping?
- No.
I am reveling.
You have not the slightest inkling...
how this feels.
After all this time,
after so many centuries,
to finally create something.
I'm going to open a First Age bottle.
I have been saving it.
Celebrimbor...
Are you my friend?
Yes, of course.
Why?
Because there is no
place for half-truths
between those who've worked
so close as you and I.
Oh...
And yet there is much you do not know.
Much I want to tell you.
Only...
You're afraid.
You see? I've never been able
to hide anything from you.
Well...
Be at ease.
Whatever it is you wish to say to me,
I shall receive it with an open heart.
I did not come here to
toast the Elven Rings.
But to plead with you
to make Rings for Men.
Rings for Men?
- You saved the Elves.
- Uh...
Elves are not Men.
Men are covetous.
The risks of, of
corruption are far greater.
Even if I did wish to forge more Rings,
the Dwarves would never
provide the mithril.
I think you'll find the Dwarves
facing a dilemma all their own.
What dilemma? What are you
talking about, Halbrand?
My name is not Halbrand.
What?
When Galadriel discovered
the truth, she cast me out.
And I dare not risk the
same happening with you.
I... I take it then you are not a King.
No. Not a King.
Not a Southlander.
Not even a... mortal.
What are you?
There are forces in this
world beyond evil, Celebrimbor.
And sometimes, they send aid,
in the form of an envoy.
A... A messenger, sent to bring
guidance to the ears of the wise.
Uh...
What sort of guidance?
Mordor's rise was but the beginning.
At this very moment,
all Middle-earth balances
on the brink of the abyss.
Soon, every realm will fall.
Not just Elves, but Dwarves. And Men.
The darkness is growing stronger.
And the Rings of Power are our
last hope of restoring the light.
You and I have work to do.
You cannot expect me to believe
that you are a, a messenger
from the Valar sent to...
Halbrand?
Halbrand!
I have walked through the dust
and the deserts of far-away lands,
in search of an artist possessing
the craft to save all Middle-earth.
A storm is coming, Celebrimbor.
I can bring you the knowledge
none other possesses.
I can unlock your grandest abilities.
And when our work is complete,
never again will the world overlook
you as the mere scion of Fëanor
but forevermore revere you...
The Lord of the Rings.
You need not bow to me.
But I have beheld your natural form.
Rise.
Our work begins now.
What am I to call you?
I am your partner.
No more, no less.
A sharer of gifts.
Annatar.
Lord of Gifts.
You summoned me.
You have new orders, Commander.
You depart for Eregion at first
light, with five of our bravest Elves.
I...
Thank you for reconsidering.
It is not I, you ought to thank.
Elrond.
I am very grateful you have
decided to join my company.
I'm afraid you misunderstand, Galadriel.
Elrond's task is not
to join your company.
But to lead it.
What is it? Is it Elrond?
It's some sort of invitation...
from Lord Celebrimbor.
He wants the Dwarves to come to Eregion.
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.MY-SUBS.com -